<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://quiltmc.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://quiltmc.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-04-14T22:55:59+00:00</updated><id>https://quiltmc.org/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Quilt Project</title><subtitle>The mod-loader that cares.</subtitle><author><name>QuiltMC</name></author><entry><title type="html">Introducing BlanketCon!</title><link href="https://quiltmc.org/blog/2022/03/29/introducing-blanketcon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing BlanketCon!" /><published>2022-03-29T07:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-29T07:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quiltmc.org/blog/2022/03/29/introducing-blanketcon</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quiltmc.org/blog/2022/03/29/introducing-blanketcon/"><![CDATA[<p>Heya! Lemma here to announce a big project we’ve been working on for a while now! From May 6th to May 7th this year, ModFest and Quilt are proud to be hosting <strong>BlanketCon</strong>, an in-game Minecraft modding convention powered by Quilt Loader! We’ll be making a custom world where you can check out old favorites and newcomers alike! Come talk to devs and attend panels, keynotes, and more!</p>

<!-- MORE -->

<p>If you’re a Minecraft mod developer, <strong>we want you here at BlanketCon</strong>! Submit whatever mods you’d like to feature in the con; size or poularity doesn’t matter! The server will be running on the Quilt Loader beta, with support for both Fabric and Quilt mods, but if you develop for Forge, Sponge, Paper, or any other modding framework, you’re still more than welcome to hold an event - despite being Quilt-run, we want this to be a celebration of Minecraft modding as a whole! You can apply to host a booth or an at-con event at <a href="https://blanketcon.modfest.net/signup">https://blanketcon.modfest.net/signup/</a>!</p>

<p>The con server will open on May 5th at 6 PM UTC, with the opening ceremony beginning an hour later! You can see the full schedule as it’s created, as well as all confirmed booths on the BlanketCon site at <a href="https://blanketcon.modfest.net">blanketcon.modfest.net</a>!</p>

<p>If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to ask in the <a href="https://discord.gg/gn543Ee">ModFest</a> or <a href="https://discord.quiltmc.org">Quilt</a> discords! I hope to see you all there!</p>]]></content><author><name>QuiltMC</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Heya! Lemma here to announce a big project we’ve been working on for a while now! From May 6th to May 7th this year, ModFest and Quilt are proud to be hosting BlanketCon, an in-game Minecraft modding convention powered by Quilt Loader! We’ll be making a custom world where you can check out old favorites and newcomers alike! Come talk to devs and attend panels, keynotes, and more!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://quiltmc.org/assets/img/logo-square.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://quiltmc.org/assets/img/logo-square.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Quilt enters Beta</title><link href="https://quiltmc.org/blog/2022/03/22/quilt-enters-beta/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quilt enters Beta" /><published>2022-03-22T05:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T05:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quiltmc.org/blog/2022/03/22/quilt-enters-beta</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quiltmc.org/blog/2022/03/22/quilt-enters-beta/"><![CDATA[<p>In February’s final bi-weekly developer meeting (which you can listen to <a href="https://anchor.fm/quiltmc-dev-meetings">as a podcast</a>), an exciting announcement was made: <strong>Quilt is releasing its first beta on April 20th, 2022</strong>.</p>

<!-- MORE -->

<p>It’s a huge milestone in our development process, and we could never have done it without our <a href="https://quiltmc.org/about/teams/">incredible teams</a> and supporting community.</p>

<p>It is important to remember that this is a <strong>beta</strong>, not a full release. Beta software is intended for testing, ironing out issues and having space to develop features ahead of a full release. This means that a beta release will have some features missing, and may be unstable.</p>

<h2 id="instability">Instability</h2>

<p>Beta software is inherently unstable. This means that there could be a lot of bugs and crashes, but it also means that <em>anything could change at any time, with no regard for compatibility between one version and the next.</em></p>

<p>It may be frustrating, but trying different approaches and iterating is an essential part of our development, and during this pre-release stage it is essential to not be held back by backwards compatibility.</p>

<h2 id="missing-features">Missing Features</h2>

<p>Beta software is also generally missing features that will be included in the full release, and Quilt is no exception. All our projects are at a stage where we feel that they are usable, but most of them are still missing features that will be included in the final release. Namely:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Mods will be built using a fork of Fabric’s Loom with Intermediary, instead of Quilt-Gradle with Hashed MojMap.</li>
  <li>The CHASM bytecode transformer is not yet ready for use and will not be available.</li>
  <li>Loader plugins will not exist.</li>
  <li>QSL (Quilt Standard Libraries) will not be automatically downloaded as a dependency.</li>
  <li>Many QSL Modules will not be available to use.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="why-were-releasing-now">Why we’re releasing now</h2>

<p>To address the elephant in the room, we’re not releasing Quilt on 4/20 for the memes. April 20th is actually the one-year anniversary of the Community Discord server, a very significant event in Quilt’s history. Besides this, we’re releasing our tools in an unfinished state for two reasons:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Quilt is relatively unknown outside its community, and we hope that by showing that Quilt is more than just an idea, the project will gain some traction, and start being taken more seriously by people in the modding sphere.</li>
  <li>Both our developers and our (future) users are very important to us, and we want your feedback and ideas on how to improve what we’ve made, while we still have the flexibility of being in the development stage to change and break things, without having to worry about backwards compatibility.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="stay-in-the-know">Stay in the Know</h2>

<p>While we are currently confident that we can make the April 20th target, the truth is that software development is often unpredictable, and estimates aren’t always representative of when a target is met. If you want to stay up-to-date with developments, we recommend joining our <a href="https://discord.quiltmc.org">Community Discord Server</a>, and/or <a href="https://twitter.com/Quilt_MC">following us on Twitter</a>.</p>

<p>You can even <a href="https://quiltmc.org/feed.xml">subscribe to this blog via RSS</a> and get updates delivered straight to your RSS reader of choice.</p>

<p>We also hold a Public Developer Meeting on the <a href="https://discord.quiltmc.org/toolchain">Toolchain Discord Server</a> every second Saturday at 5PM UTC, where the teams get together and discuss the progress made on their respective projects, and also answer questions from the community. Even though it’s called a Developer meeting, anyone interested in Quilt’s future development is welcome.</p>

<h2 id="get-involved">Get Involved</h2>

<p>If you want to get involved, we could always use some extra help. A list of current openings for positions on our various teams can be found on the <a href="&quot;https://quiltmc.org/openings/&quot;">Openings page</a>, but if none of them speak to you, or if you want to contribute without joining a team, the best thing to do is to join the <a href="https://discord.quiltmc.org/toolchain">Toolchain Discord Server</a> and offer your expertise.</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>We’d like to thank everyone who has come with us on the journey so far, including our developers and our wonderful community. This is Quilt’s biggest step since we ran out of GitHub Actions minutes and had to go public, and we never could’ve done it without all of you.</p>

<p>Quilt is closer than ever, and we can’t wait.</p>]]></content><author><name>QuiltMC</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In February’s final bi-weekly developer meeting (which you can listen to as a podcast), an exciting announcement was made: Quilt is releasing its first beta on April 20th, 2022.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://quiltmc.org/assets/img/logo-square.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://quiltmc.org/assets/img/logo-square.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Quilt’s (VERY LATE) October Update</title><link href="https://quiltmc.org/blog/2021/11/10/quilt-oct-update/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quilt’s (VERY LATE) October Update" /><published>2021-11-10T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-11-10T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quiltmc.org/blog/2021/11/10/quilt-oct-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quiltmc.org/blog/2021/11/10/quilt-oct-update/"><![CDATA[<p>It is now <em>well</em> past the End of October and closer to Halloween then I’d like to admit. Here is some of the more fleshed out updates about the Quilt Project:</p>

<!-- MORE -->

<h2 id="quilt-mappings-are-now-usable-in-loom">Quilt Mappings are now usable in Loom!</h2>
<p>Have you wanted to use mappings other than Yarn or MojMap?</p>

<p>Quilt Mappings is a Yarn derivative that allows inspiration from MojMap. This allows for Quilt Mappings to map the obscure constants in Minecraft code and more.</p>

<p>However, this can mean that Quilt Mappings maybe be different from Yarn.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/OroArmor/quilt-mappings-on-loom">The provided gradle plugin</a> allows Quilt Mappings to be used in Loom and Fabric environments. Currently, it is 1.17.1+ only; with no plans of backporting to earlier versions.</p>

<p>Benefits of Quilt Mappings:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Faster turn around.
    <ul>
      <li>For the past couple weeks, Quilt Mappings has been out before intermediary. While this doesn’t help too much in loom, it is something to look forward to in the future.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Consistent names.
    <ul>
      <li>Quilt Mapping names are never mismatched, meaning you won’t find issues where names swap between versions.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Familiarity of Yarn with the completeness of MojMap.
    <ul>
      <li>While not complete, Quilt Mappings has the goal of 100% mapping coverage for Minecraft. Any help toward this goal would be appreciated as well!</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<h3 id="how-to-use-quilt-mapping-gradle-plugin">How to use Quilt Mapping (Gradle Plugin)</h3>

<p>How to use Quilt Mappings:</p>

<h4 id="settingsgradle">settings.gradle</h4>

<div class="language-groovy highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="n">pluginManagement</span> <span class="o">{</span>
    <span class="n">repositories</span> <span class="o">{</span>
        <span class="n">maven</span> <span class="o">{</span> <span class="n">url</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">"https://maven.oroarmor.com"</span> <span class="o">}</span>
    <span class="o">}</span>
<span class="o">}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h4 id="buildgradle">build.gradle</h4>

<div class="language-groovy highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="n">plugins</span> <span class="o">{</span>
  <span class="c1">// ...</span>
  <span class="n">id</span> <span class="s2">"quilt-mappings-on-loom"</span> <span class="n">version</span> <span class="s2">"2.0.0"</span>
<span class="o">}</span>

<span class="c1">// ...</span>

<span class="n">dependencies</span> <span class="o">{</span>
   <span class="n">mappings</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="n">loom</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">layered</span> <span class="o">{</span>
      <span class="n">addLayer</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="n">quiltmappings</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">mappings</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="s2">"org.quiltmc:quilt-mappings:${minecraft_version}+build.${project.quilt_mappings}:v2"</span><span class="o">,</span> <span class="kc">true</span><span class="o">))</span>
   <span class="o">})</span>
<span class="o">}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="new-moderators">New Moderators</h2>
<p>Quilt’s community spaces are always looking for new moderators. If you think you’d be a good fit and like to be involved, you can submit an application via ModMail.</p>

<p>Some key documents to be aware of <strong>before</strong> applying:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://quiltmc.org/community/code-of-conduct.html">The Quilt Code of Conduct</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://quiltmc.org/community/rules.html">Quilt’s Rules</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://quiltmc.org/community/moderation.html">Our Moderation Ethos</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/QuiltMC/rfcs/blob/master/structure/0007-community-team.md">RFC-7 (The Community Team Structure)</a></li>
</ul>

<p>If the qualities outlined in the above documents, seem like you… please step forward and apply. The interview proccess will follow the steps outlined in RFC-7 (TL;DR):</p>
<ul>
  <li>Apply Via ModMail</li>
  <li>Interview with a Community Manager (and the wider Community Team)</li>
  <li>Community team holds a vote based on the interview</li>
  <li>Result of the vote given to interviewee, and if successful the applicant will become a Trainee Moderator</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>ToffeeMax</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is now well past the End of October and closer to Halloween then I’d like to admit. Here is some of the more fleshed out updates about the Quilt Project:]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://quiltmc.org/assets/img/logo-square.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://quiltmc.org/assets/img/logo-square.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Quilt September Update</title><link href="https://quiltmc.org/blog/2021/09/19/quilt-sept-update/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quilt September Update" /><published>2021-09-19T15:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-19T15:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quiltmc.org/blog/2021/09/19/quilt-sept-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quiltmc.org/blog/2021/09/19/quilt-sept-update/"><![CDATA[<p>It has been a few months since the last update on the Quilt Project.</p>

<p>Quilt has progressed far since that initial “This is Quilt” blog with: new teams set up; several important RFCs being published and developments in many key areas.</p>

<!-- MORE -->

<h2 id="clean-room-rfc-33">Clean Room RFC-33</h2>

<p><a href="https://github.com/QuiltMC/rfcs/blob/master/rfc/0033-quilt-mappings-and-clean-room.md">RFC-33 has been merged</a>. This RFC changes how Quilt is dealing with other mappings (such as MojMap, MCP and Yarn).</p>

<p>Key Take-Aways:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Quilt’s fork of Yarn will be renamed to “Quilt Mappings” (QM)</li>
  <li>All restrictions on referencing mappings projects (other than Quilt Mappings) within Quilt’s community and development spaces will be lifted</li>
</ul>

<p>The reasoning, possible outcomes, drawbacks and smaller changes are outlined further in the RFC document.</p>

<h3 id="quilt-mappings">Quilt Mappings</h3>
<p>As noted above, Quilt Mappings (QM) exist and are open to contributions.</p>

<h2 id="quilt-standard-library-qsl">Quilt Standard Library (QSL)</h2>

<p>The Quilt Standard Library (Quilt’s separation of the current Fabric API into distinct modules – see <a href="https://github.com/QuiltMC/rfcs/blob/master/rfc/0009-qsl-structure.md">RFC-9</a>), now has the resource loader and base (for events).</p>

<p>We are looking for help testing the resource loader. This can be done by using the snapshot maven repo with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">org.quiltmc.qsl.core:resource-loader:1.0.0-SNAPSHOT</code>.</p>

<p>QSL is seeing new additions on top of the reorganization into modules.</p>

<h2 id="quilt-mod-json">Quilt Mod JSON</h2>
<p>The Quilt Mod JSON has now been mostly implemented. The design of this is outlined in <a href="https://github.com/QuiltMC/rfcs/blob/master/specification/0002-quilt.mod.json.md">RFC-2</a>.</p>

<p>The majority of the work left is smooth out issues in the loader.</p>

<h2 id="quiltflower">QuiltFlower</h2>
<p>QuiltFlower (Quilt’s Fork/Maintained version of FernFlower/ForgeFlower) has seen some smaller changes.</p>

<p>These changes should make de-complied code more readable. An example of this can be seen in the following images:</p>

<p><strong>Output produced by FabricFlower</strong>
<img src="https://i.imgur.com/M81I32X.png" alt="Output Produced by Fabric Flower" /></p>

<p><strong>Same output, produced using QuiltFlower</strong>
<img src="https://i.imgur.com/1ICd4Nb.png" alt="Same output produced by Quilt Flower" /></p>

<h2 id="new-moderators">New Moderators</h2>
<p>Quilt’s community spaces are always looking for new moderators. If you think you’d be a good fit and like to be involved, you can submit an application via ModMail.</p>

<p>Some key documents to be aware of <strong>before</strong> applying:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://quiltmc.org/community/code-of-conduct.html">The Quilt Code of Conduct</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://quiltmc.org/community/rules.html">Quilt’s Rules</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://quiltmc.org/community/moderation.html">Our Moderation Ethos</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/QuiltMC/rfcs/blob/master/structure/0007-community-team.md">RFC-7 (The Community Team Structure)</a></li>
</ul>

<p>If the qualities outlined in the above documents, seem like you… please step forward and apply. The interview process will follow the steps outlined in RFC-7 (TL;DR):</p>
<ul>
  <li>Apply Via ModMail</li>
  <li>Interview with a Community Manager (and the wider Community Team)</li>
  <li>Community team holds a vote based on the interview</li>
  <li>Result of the vote given to interviewee, and if successful the applicant will become a Trainee Moderator</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="modding-with-quilt--fabric">Modding with Quilt &amp; Fabric</h2>

<h3 id="can-i-mod-with-quilt-at-the-moment">Can I mod with Quilt at the moment?</h3>

<p>It is currently not possible to mod with the Quilt framework.</p>

<p>However, progress has been made. We are currently waiting on a Gradle Plugin.</p>

<p><strong>We are looking for contributors.</strong> If you would like to help out with this part of the project, please reach out in <a href="https://canary.discord.com/channels/833872081585700874/884090296068091965/885866814410723358">#build-tools-general</a> and express interest. A member of the relevant team will reach out.</p>

<h3 id="are-things-still-compatible-with-fabric">Are things still compatible with Fabric?</h3>

<p>Things are largely compatible with loading mods.</p>

<p>Mixin Plugins may not be possible to maintain compatibility.  We may consider contributing to some mods that use them, to aid in replacing them.</p>

<h2 id="round-off">Round-off</h2>
<p>That is all for now! When there are more things to talk about, they will be published here; for more bleeding edge changes and updates on the project, follow along on our <a href="https://discord.quiltmc.org">Discords</a>.</p>

<p>Thank-you to the Quilt Project’s team for helping flesh this out; it would have otherwise been just an update on moderators.</p>]]></content><author><name>ToffeeMax</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It has been a few months since the last update on the Quilt Project. Quilt has progressed far since that initial “This is Quilt” blog with: new teams set up; several important RFCs being published and developments in many key areas.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://quiltmc.org/assets/img/logo-square.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://quiltmc.org/assets/img/logo-square.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">This is Quilt</title><link href="https://quiltmc.org/blog/2021/04/20/this-is-quilt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This is Quilt" /><published>2021-04-20T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-20T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quiltmc.org/blog/2021/04/20/this-is-quilt</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quiltmc.org/blog/2021/04/20/this-is-quilt/"><![CDATA[<p>This is the Quilt Project: An open, community-driven modding toolchain designed primarily for Minecraft. Quilt builds on many of the technologies developed by <a href="https://fabricmc.net/">the Fabric Project</a> and is designed to take what worked well and expand on it further.</p>

<!-- MORE -->

<h2 id="why-the-fork">Why the Fork?</h2>

<p>While the Fabric Project has made significant progress towards an open and advanced mod loader, it has recently slowed down in technical innovation and failed to address several organizational issues. There are a number of changes the Quilt Project will put into place in the future to differentiate ourselves:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Governmental Structure – Quilt’s organizational structure has been designed with openness in mind; no one person holds all the keys.</li>
  <li>Separation of Concerns – Those in charge of technical concerns should not be making important community decisions, and vice versa. Quilt’s teams each control a very specific aspect of the project.</li>
  <li>Quilt Loader Plugins – Will allow other parties to change mod loading behavior in new and exciting ways.</li>
  <li>Dependency Downloading – Users will no longer have to download every single dependency for each of their mods.</li>
  <li>Cleaner Bytecode Modifications – A safe, deterministic alternative to “Mixin” or modifying bytecode by hand.</li>
  <li>Faster Iteration &amp; Experimentation – The Quilt project aims to fail fast. We would rather try something and fix it then spend countless months debating whether to move forward with it in the first place.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="important-documents-and-rfcs">Important Documents and RFCs</h2>

<p>Quilt makes use of a Request for Comment system to drive major organizational changes. The RFCs are designed to make clear what changes are on the horizon, allow for comment from the community and as a maintained location for how specific parts of The Quilt Project work (eg Governance).</p>

<p>You can view these documents (accepted and not) via our <a href="https://github.com/QuiltMC/rfcs">GitHub Repository</a>; please use this space to submit new RFCs and comment on currently open ones.</p>

<p>The process of RFCs is outlined in <a href="https://github.com/QuiltMC/rfcs/blob/master/structure/0001-rfc-process.md">RFC-0001</a>.</p>

<h2 id="who-is-involved">Who is involved?</h2>

<p>To view an approximate membership, our <a href="https://github.com/QuiltMC">GitHub organization</a> is a good starting place. This list is not exhaustive as it may not include members who are part of the community team.</p>

<h2 id="can-i-mod-on-fabric-and-quilt">Can I mod on Fabric and Quilt?</h2>

<p>Fabric mods will be able to run on Quilt initially. There may be a point in the future where this is no longer possible.</p>

<h2 id="i-have-more-questions">I have more questions!</h2>

<p>We have written a FAQ which hopes to provide answers to some common questions. If something is not covered there, please ask on our <a href="https://discord.quiltmc.org">Discord</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Haven King</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is the Quilt Project: An open, community-driven modding toolchain designed primarily for Minecraft. Quilt builds on many of the technologies developed by the Fabric Project and is designed to take what worked well and expand on it further.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://quiltmc.org/assets/img/logo-square.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://quiltmc.org/assets/img/logo-square.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>